[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Good morning, brothers and sisters.
Happy Father's Day.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Some of you may remember what it was
like to have your dad hold your hand when you cross the road.
That's a child.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And that is kind of like a big hand wrapping entirely
around your little hands.
And you had nothing to fear, because you know
that he would never let go.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But not everyone have warm memories when
it comes to their father's hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Some remember a hand that was never present.
Others remember the hands that would lash out or even hurt
others.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And for some of us, what they miss the most on these Father's
Days is a hand that they can no longer hold.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So our passage today is short, just four verses,
but the word "hands" here appears twice.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And through this verse, Jesus wants
to reveal to us what kind of Father our Heavenly Father is.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And what kind of hands he has.
And by the end of the sermon, we will know these three things.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
First, whose hands does the Father's hold?
And second, why does Jesus say that no one
is able to snatch them out of the Father's hand?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And third, what does the phrase "I and the Father are one"
have to do with Father's Day?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
If you're ready, we'll read our passage today.
My sheep hear my voice, and I know them,
and they follow me.
I give them eternal life, and they will never perish.
And no one will snatch them out of my hand.
My Father, who has given them to me, is greater than all.
And no one is able to snatch them out of the Father's hand.
I and the Father are one.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So let's first look at the context
in which Jesus gave these words.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Verse 22 tells us that it was the festival of dedication
during the wintertime.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So the festival of dedication actually
commemorates the Maccabean-era purification of the temple,
when the temple, defiled by a foreign king,
was rededicated as holy to the Lord.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And it was at this festival that a group of Jews
surrounded Jesus and demanded him,
how long will you keep us guessing?
If you're the Christ, just tell us plainly.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Jesus did not answer them directly with I am or I'm not.
Instead, he spoke about sheep.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And this raises our first question today.
So why didn't Jesus simply answer them yes or no
to the are you the Christ questions?
But instead, he spoke of my sheep hear my voice.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In fact, his very way of answering it
is in and of itself the answer.
So let us follow the passage questions by questions,
beginning with the first one.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Jesus' answer to the questions, are you the Christ,
was not a theological argument, but a description
of a relationship.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The three verbs in verse 27 are beautiful.
The sheep hear my voice, I know them, and they follow me.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In the original language, hear is not just
mere physical hearing, but discerning and hearing.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Like a child in a crowd that instantly recognized
their father's voice.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And know is not just knowing some facts about someone,
but a deep knowing found in relationship.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So Jesus already said in verse 14 and 15,
I know my sheep, and my sheep know me,
just as the father knows me, and I know the father.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In other words, the knowing between the sheep
and the shepherd is actually rooted
in the knowing between the father and the son.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We are known by God because of the deep mutual knowing that
has already exists between the father and the son.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And now, once we recognize who the shepherd is,
the second questions follow.
How does this shepherd keep his sheep?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And why does the word "hen" appear twice
in such a short passage?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So let us begin from the climax here in verse 28.
"I give them eternal life, and they will never perish,
and no one will snatch them out of my hand."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So two words here, no forwarding.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH] First, "will never perish"
is a double negative, an emphatic expression
meaning absolutely forever, they will not perish.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Second, "snatch," the word, is the same word
used in verse 12, describing a wolf seizing the sheep
and scattering the flock.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
In other words, Jesus is not saying that there is no danger
or no fierce wolf.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
What he's saying is no matter how great the wolf power is,
it cannot seize them.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Then notice this.
In verse 28, it says, "out of my hand."
And verse 29, it says, "out of the Father's hands."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Why does Jesus have to say the same thing twice,
once using my hand and the other time using the Father's hand?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The answer can be found in verse 30.
I and the Father are one.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This is not two hands in the tug of war.
It is the same grip and the same power.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The sheep held in the son's hands
are also held in the Father's hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This is a double assurance, and yet it is the same hand.
And verse 29, it has a crucial phase,
that this hand is greater than all.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This leads us to the first misconception
that we need to address.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Many people live an exhausting life,
even after they come to faith.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Because they think that salvation
is like a game of holding on to the Father's hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The moment they loosen the grip, or grow weak, or stumble,
they will fall and lose their salvation.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So they live in constant fear that they are not
holding tight enough.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But if we look at our passage from verse 27 to 30,
none of the verses says that the sheep
must hold on to their shepherd.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
From the beginning to the end, it
is always the shepherd's hand that holds the sheep.
It is the Father's hand that holds the sheep.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Return to the earlier image that a child crossing the street
is safe.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Not because he grips his father's hand with all
his strength.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But because of his father's hands that wraps around
the little one entirely.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Even if the child lets go, the father does not.
Your salvation does not depend on how tightly you hold on to.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And that hand is greater than all.
Finally, we come to the weightiest statement here,
which brings up the third and final question.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
What does the word "one" mean when Jesus says,
"I and the Father are one"?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The word "one" here in the original Greek
is "neuter," not "masculine" or "not masculine."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This grammatical distinction is important
because Jesus is not saying that the Father and the Son
are the same person.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
What he's saying is that the Father and the Son
are completely one in nature, in will, in action, and power.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
They are two distinct persons, yet one God, one will,
and one hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This addressed our second misconception.
"I and the Father are one" does not
mean that Jesus and the Father are indistinguishable.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And the Jewish crowd, they actually understood exactly
what Jesus meant, which is why in the next verse,
they immediately pick up the stones
and trying to stone Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And the reason is because Jesus claims that he, a mere man,
claimed to be God.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Jesus was declaring, I am one with the Father in essence,
will, and work, and what I do is what the Father does.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It is precisely because the Son and the Father
are one that Jesus would later say,
"Whoever has seen the Father has seen me.
Whoever has seen me has seen the Father."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And this is the most important statement for Father's Day
today.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
If we want to know what kind of Father our Heavenly Father is--
We don't have to guess.
We simply look at Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Look at how Jesus treats his sheep,
knowing them, giving them eternal life,
and never letting go.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And that is what our Heavenly Father is like.
In fact, the setting of these words being spoken
on the festival of dedication make it even more wonderful.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
This festival commemorates the rededication,
making holy again what has been defiled.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And in verse 36, Jesus described himself
as the one whom the Father consecrated and sent
into the world.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Jesus reveals himself as the truly consecrated one.
He came to bring back the loss and the woundership
into the Father's hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So in response to this Heavenly Father who is greater than all
and never lets go, how might we respond to this Father's day?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
First, if the word "Father" brings you grief,
let the Heavenly Father redefine what "Fathers" mean.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We naturally project our image of an earthly father
onto our Heavenly Father sometimes.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
If your father was absent, you may
feel that God is also distant and would abandon you.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And if your father was harsh or frightening,
you may feel that God is always ready to punish you as well.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But when Jesus says, "I and the Father are one,"
it means this.
To know the Heavenly Father, you don't
have to guess through the lens of your earthly father, who
disappoint you, but instead look through Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
However Jesus treats you is how the Heavenly Father treats you.
This week, find some quiet time to bring a disappointment
and your wounds from your earthly father
before the Heavenly Father.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And you can ask him to heal your understanding of the word "Father"
through the image of Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And this is Ken's testimony.
So my father was an absent father.
From a very young age, he was not
there for many of the important moments in my life.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Whether it was the secondary school graduation, university,
or even post-graduation ceremony, he never showed up.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Every time, I desperately hoped that he would appear and say,
"You did well.
I'm so proud of you."
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
When I came to faith, I thought that this pain
would just naturally go away.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But then I discovered that this sense of not being a firm
can be projected onto the Heavenly Father.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Deep down in me, I felt that I was never doing enough,
that I have to keep striving to earn the Heavenly Father's
approval.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
It was only until later when the Heavenly Father healed me
and helped me to redefine things through Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And he showed me how deeply I'm loved.
And I slowly move out from under the shadow
of not being reassured.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So I would like to encourage everyone to do the same,
to bring your disappointments and wounds
about your earthly father honestly
before your Heavenly Father.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And ask him to heal your understanding of the word
"father" through the image of Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Second, if you're longing for a hand that you can no longer
hold, his father say--
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Remember that your father is in our Heavenly Father's hand.
The scripture says no one is able to snatch them
from the father's hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
If the father that you're missing belongs to the Lord--
Then this is the promise for you.
Not even death can snatch him from the Heavenly Father's hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Third, if you are a father today,
ask the Lord to help us and learn to be like him.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
None of us as fathers are perfect.
We fail, we lose our temper, our absence,
and we disappoint our children.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But our Heavenly Father has given us
a model to follow, to truly know your children,
not just the greats, but to truly know them, to hold them,
and to not easily let go.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
You don't need to be a perfect father, but through the Lord,
you can be a father who never lets go.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
The kind of father who, even when your children stumble,
or grow weak, or disappoint you, that you still
don't release that hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Because this is exactly what the Heavenly Father has always
done for us.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So let's return to the questions that we have at the beginning
and answer them together.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So first question, whose hand does the father hold?
He holds every sheep that hears his voice and follows him,
not because the sheep is good enough or hold tightly enough,
but because the shepherd knows and has chosen that sheep.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Second, what is the basis of our security?
It is not on how tightly we hold on to,
but in a hand that is greater than all,
that no one can snatch us away from.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And third, what does I and the father are one
have to do with Father's Day?
It is because the son and the father are one
that we see the Heavenly Father's heart clearly
through Jesus, a father who never lets go.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
So some questions for us to reflect on.
When you hear the word "father," what
is the first thing that comes to your heart?
Has that feeling quietly shaped how you
understand our Heavenly Father?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And on this Father's Day, are you
willing to let the Heavenly Father hold you again
through the image of Jesus?
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
Let's pray together.
Dear Heavenly Father, thank you for revealing to us
what kind of father you are through your son, Jesus.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We thank you that you are not a father who is far off or cold
or always ready to punish us.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
But you are a father who knows us, who comes to find us,
who holds us with a hand greater than all.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
May you heal every wound from our earthly father
that we carry.
And may those who have been hurt by their fathers
or those who are missing their fathers today
be held anew by your hand.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
And may you help every father among us to learn from your
hands the one that never lets go.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We give this Father's Day into your hands.
In Jesus' name, we pray.
Amen.
[NON-ENGLISH SPEECH]
We wish you all a wonderful Father's Day.